this video is sponsored by Wizards of
the Coast modern Horizon 3 is the new
straight to Modern set that brings some
fantastic reprints to Modern for the
first time as well as some powerful new
cards we've never seen before so let's
go over the top 10 most powerful cards
from this set and the decks you should
be adding them to of course we have to
give some honory mentions to a few cards
these are cards that might not have a
home that they can slot into right away
but will no doubt find a home soon first
we have the untapped mdfc spell lands
monocolored spells that you can play as
tapped lands or you can pay three life
to have them come into play
untapped asides from being fuel for the
beler the flexibility these spells offer
are unparalleled I will be very
surprised if at least sink into stuper
and bogot troller don't see some level
of play almost immediately our next
honorary mention is Arena of Glory a
land that effectively own only costs one
red mana on a future turn and gives you
two Hasty red Mana in return most of the
red aggro deck creatures already have
haste and can't really make use of this
ability but this land might be better
off suited in decks looking to cast big
threats that could take advantage of
attacking straight away a hasty 66 Merk
tide perhaps or maybe a hasty ulamog the
defiler and for our final honorary
mention we have dream tide whale a three
Mana 75 with with Vanishing two and
whenever a player casts their second
spell each turn proliferate Now where's
the drawback on this card how is any
deck playing blue not looking to cast a
bunch of can trips and the fact that
your opponent can trigger this card and
the fact that you just simply
proliferate and not just put a single
time counter on the whale surely this
card will have to see
suplay okay onto the main list now this
list isn't in any particular order this
is just 10 powerful cards that you
should be keeping an eye out for in your
future games having said that let's
start with arguably the most powerful
card in the whole set ugan Labyrinth a
land that Taps for a single colorless
but if you Exile a colorless card from
your hand with cost seven or greater
when you play it it Taps for two and on
top of that you can return the exiled
card to your hand by tapping the land
who would have thought that a land that
can tap for two Mana with a relatively
small activation requirement wouldn't be
powerful the deck this land likely ends
up in is either Tron or the new elrazi
deck two decks known for playing seven
or more cost threats and we're getting
plenty of new high- cost bombs that
could go into either of these decks
devour of Destiny n Drifter and even the
three new eldrazi Titans and just for
comparison city of traitors and ancient
tomb are two of the strongest lands
played in Legacy and we have haven't
even mentioned that technically exiling
a seven drop from your hand is not
really a drawback but you're simply
protecting that card from a thought Seas
or a grief speaking of cards that cost
seven or more the second card on the
list is emerle the world and new the
latest version of this elazi Titan a 12
Mana 1212 that on cast you gain control
of all creatures Target player controls
it has flying protection from spells and
from permanence that were cast this turn
and when emle the world in you leaves
the battlefield sacrifice All Creatures
you control and finally it has Madness
if you discard this card you can pay six
colorless mana and cast the emerle
instead now if you want to learn more
about what those abilities mean and how
you can interact with this card be sure
to watch this
explainer with this card I think it's
really important to focus on two things
here number one this card is going to be
cast for six Mana a large majy of the
time underworld cookbook and smugg as
copter are two really efficient ways
that allow you to discard emerle number
two that protection ability is extremely
hard to get around in the current modern
meta board wipes are far and few between
and most decks are simply running single
targeted removal once this hits the
board it's very unlikely it's getting
removed next we have white Orchard
Phantom a two minor 22 with flying and
first strike and when when it etbs you
can destroy up to one target non-basic
land its controller May search the
library for a basic land card put it
onto the battlefield tapped then Shuffle
there are two ways you can play White
Orchard Phantom the most obvious way is
to Simply use it on your opponent's ugan
Labyrinth or fian Tower or you can treat
it like mono white ramp and use it on
your own flagstones of tqu or
indestructible lands white Orchard
Phantom will easily find a home in death
and taxes St decks as they often run
flickerwisp and eldrazi displacer to
re-trigger effects like Solitude thought
not Seer and Sky clave Apparition with
the amount of powerful non-basic lands
coming to this set there is no way that
this card doesn't see play next we have
two powerful tools that will likely both
fit in the same deck murol first we have
harbringer of the Seas which will
henceforth be known as flood Moon flood
moon is a three cost 22 Muro that turns
all non-basic lands into Islands now for
those of you who have somehow never
played against a blood moon or a magot
of the moon this ability completely
removes all abilities from non-basic
Clans and leaves them with tap add a
blue shifting Woodlands Island
Monumental henge Island shocklands all
of them are now Islands this can
absolutely be devastating for a lot of
decks in modern and unlike Magus of the
Moon flood moon has the oh so important
creature type murol which means thanks
to Cavern of souls your flood moon is
not getting countered if Tron and
eldrazi start to rear their heads be
sure to see a lot of this card flood
moon is an excellent card and because of
that you're going to need a way to
protect it especially when you've tapped
out to cast it luckily we have our next
new and Powerful card flare of denial a
three Mana counter spell where you can
instead sacrifice a non-token creature
instead of paying the Spell's Mana cost
this card of course is comparable to
force of negation from the original
modern Horizon set however two things to
note negation free alternative casting
cost is only active on your opponent's
turn making it weak against removal that
is likely to be cast on your turn and
secondly it can only hit non-creature
spells flare of denial gives the murol
deck excellent Flex ability as it
literally gives you an answer to
everything and cashing in a tide shaper
or a Muk trickster is a small price to
pay to stop your board from being wiped
or stopping a crucial combo our next
card is another excellent Stacks piece
winter Moon a two minor artifact that
says players can't untap more than one
non-basic gland during their untap steps
a clear throwback in homage to Winter
orb and Blood Moon this art fact is
perfect for one of my favorite decks
monor red prison a deck that literally
looks to lock your opponents out of the
game by hampering their ability to cast
spells and attack with creatures the
deck usually looks to play blood moon or
Chalice of the Void on turn two but now
with winter Moon they have another
option again due to all of the great
non-basic lands that are coming with
modern Horizons 3 winter moon seems like
a very powerful card for this meta our
first flip Walker for this is tamio
inquisitive student and out of all five
walkers we're getting this one is by far
the easiest to flip tamio inquisitive
student is a one Manor 03 with flying
and whenever she attacks you investigate
and when you draw your third card in a
turn tamio transforms into tamio season
scholar a two loyalty Plains Walker that
says plus two until your next turn
whenever a creature attacks you or a
plaines Walker you control it gets - one
- 0 until end of turn and minus three
return Target instant or sorcery from
your graveyard to your hand if it's a
green card add one Mana of any color and
minus 7 draw cards equal to half the
number of cards in your library rounded
up you get an emblem with you have no
maximum hand size while tamamo's Plaines
Walker side isn't hugely impactful
getting a planes Walker in play on turn
two that will likely have four loyalty
at the end of the turn is an incredible
Advantage it's literally as simple as
playing tamio on turn one and on turn
two you draw your card for the turn
attack and then cast any number of two
Mana spells that draw two cards chart of
course deadly dispute faithful mending
or one of the countless versions of
thrill of possibility and if you're
playing a Tempo based deck I don't think
that ulating tamio is out of the
question at all tamio will easily find a
home in any of the blue red Spell
slinger decks like is it control next we
have sewing MOS spawn a four Manor 33
alrai with kicker two when you cast this
spell search your library for a land
card and put it onto the battlefield
then Shuffle so it is absolute flaw you
get a 33 body that shooters for a land
and puts it into play and that ability
triggers even if the creature gets
counted and it shoters for any land that
could be your last Tron piece or even 's
Saga to keep the value train flowing and
if you're able to kick the fungus you
get to Exile one of your opponent's
lands too and again it's an onc ability
so it's not likely to be countered and
that ability could snipe one of your
opponent's Tron lands or their own Saga
or any other utility land with alrazy
decks making a comeback this card will
likely find a home in
everyone back on the topic of lands
we've got another extremely powerful
land shifting Woodland a land that comes
into play untapped if we control a
forest and Taps for green and has an
activated ability that's locked behind
delirium when you have four or more car
types in your graveyard you can pay for
and have shifting Woodlands become a
copy of a permanent card in your
graveyard firstly I cannot believe this
doesn't have the text activate only as a
sorcery as this ability is wild one of
the first Advanced lessons you learn in
Magic is that your graveyard is a second
hand and in modern that definitely holds
true having your best card put into the
graveyard is so easy in today's meta
your opponents will even do it for you
thanks grief so being able to turn your
land into a prime eval Titan a yogam
moth a one ring or even a massive
eldrazi is super valuable and you can
even do it on your opponent's turn I
love the idea of turning shifting
Woodlands into a blood moon on your
opponent's turn and shutting off all
their man during their upkeep just keep
in mind that shifting Woodlands does not
work with Plaines Walkers and it doesn't
really work too well with sagas either
next we've got another flare flare of
cultivation a three Mana green sorcery
that searches up two basic lands and
puts one into play tapped and the other
into your hand and just like the rest of
the cycle you can cast the spell without
paying it Mana cost by sacrificing a
non-token creature while flare of
negation is entirely rea active this one
is entirely proactive and allows the
amulet Titan decks to have even more
explosive turns on turn one you play
your land for the turn and cast a boreal
Grazer putting another land into play
you then sacrifice the Grazer to the
flare putting another land into play and
one into your hand ending turn one with
three lands in play and a guaranteed
fourth land to play on turn two this
card is effectively as powerful as ugan
Labyrinth not only will this card slot
nicely into amulet Titan I can see this
card being extremely effective in Four
Color Elementals flare of cultivation is
practically a free way to get two
triggers of omnath so there we have 10
powerful cards that are launching with
modern Horizons 3 what cards are you
most looking forward to let me know in
the comments down below and as always if
you learned something be sure to like
the video and subscribe because if you
don't Wizards will make eldrazi invade
Bloom Barrow thanks for watching and
I'll see you in the next one